Guide to the Frank Durkan Papers AIA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Legal Cases, 1975-2003, 297639
  - Subseries I: Northern Ireland, 297641
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Daily News clippings, 1981; 327604 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Post clippings, 1981; 327613 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Times clippings, 1981; 327603 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry (Police Killings; Lawyer's Inquiry), 1987-1989; 327605 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Shoot to Kill Policy I, 1983-1989; 327606 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Shoot to Kill Policy II, 1983-1898; 327607 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Article - "Criminal Justice and Human Rights in Northern Ireland" in The Records of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Mar 1983; 327608 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Lawyers Correspondence I, 1983-1984; 327610 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Lawyers Correspondence II, 1983-1984; 327611 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Newspaper Clippings: Shoot to Kill, 1983-1984; 327612 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Publication - "Shoot to Kill?: The Report of the International Lawyers Inquiry into the Lethal use of Firearms by the Secruity Forces in Northern Ireland." Mercier Press. Dublin/Cork., 1984; 327614 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Publication - book review of "Shoot to Kill?" Keara M. O'Dempsey. Seton Hall Law Review. Vol. 17, no. 1, 1987; 327615 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Stalker, John: "Stalked" loose papers, 1983-1988; 327609 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Stalker, John: Stalked Newspaper Clippings, 1988; 327616 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Subseries J: Shah of Iran, 328944
    Materials in this subseries relate to the former ruling family of Iran and subsequent legal actions taken by the State of Iran against the family, suing them for their assets. These files relate to the Plaintiff who in this particular lawsuit was Ashraf Pahlavi, twin sister of the late shah of Iran, Mohammed Reza Pahlavi.
    As background, in January 16, 1979, the Shah and his wife, the empress, left Iran to live in exile after the overthrow of government and installation of Ayatollah, Ruhollah Khomeini. The Ayatollah, attempted to seek extradition from any country the Shah would visit or go to and also sought to seize all of the Shah's assets. The Ayatollah also called for the assassination of the Shan and numerous family members. The Shah came to New York City on Oct 22, 1979 for medical care and this visit led to the Iranian Hostage Crisis. After seeking refuge in other countries, the Shah finally settled in Egypt where he died July 27, 1980. The hostages were not released until January 20, 1981 after an agreement was negotiated, the Algerian Accords.
    The suit in these files refers to that brought against the royal family by the country of Iran. The case was brought to the attention of O'Dwyer and Bernstien when the Shah came to New York City for medical attention. In the opinion of the lawyers, the Ayatollah was attempting to continue its revolution in the courts of the United States by attempting to take from the Royal Family via judicial process what it could not take by force. Iran was asking the Unites States court to intervene in a political dispute between two ruling regimes in a foreign country: The Khomeini regime and the Pahlavi regime. Brian O'Dwyer argued that New York has no responsibility to provide the type of forum that the Plaintiff - the government of Iran – should be providing and therefore the suit was considered illegitimate.
    The Princess, Ashraf Pahlavi was known as an advocate of women's rights and the material documents her frequent travel to other countries promoting women's rights. She was exiled from Iran in 1951 because of her "political meddling and general objectionable behavior". She was allowed to return permanently in 1954 (See folder FOI Request Documents, 1946-1959).
    - FOI Request: Correspondence, 1987; 328945 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - FOI Request: The Shah, 1951: Background, 1948-1959; 328946 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - FOI Request: The Shah of Iran, 1957-1964; 328947 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, 1968-1973; 328948 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, 1975-1976; 328949 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, Family, Iran, 1947, 1958-1964; 328950 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, Family, Iran, 1977-1980; 328951 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pahlavi (twin sister of Shah), 1946-1975; 328952 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pavlavi, 1965-1967; 328955 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pavlavi, 1966-1979; 328953 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Legal: Islamic Republic of Iran v. Ashraf Pahlavi: Brief for Defendant-Appellant, 1983; 328954 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Legal: Islamic Republic of Iran v. Ashraf Pahlavi: Respondent's Brief, 1983; 328956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Legal: Settlement of Claim: The Government of the Islamic Repuboica of Iran, Claimant; The Government of the U.S.A., Respondent; Submitted to the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, The Hague, 1982; 328957 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Legal: Statement of Defense of the United States: Islamic Republic of Iran v. The United States, Jun 10, 1983; 328958 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Legal: Statement of Defense: Exhibits, 1979-1981, 1983; 328959 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Subseries K. U.S. v. McKinley et al (McKinley, McColgan, McCann, and Moley), 582937
    In 1990, Kevin Joseph McKinley, Seamus McColgan, Sean John McCann, and Seamus Moley were arrested in Florida and charged with buying an anti-aircraft missile and other weapons from undercover agents with the intention of providing the weapons to members of the Provisional IRA in Northern Ireland. They were found guilty and in 1991, McKinley, McColgan, and Moley were sentenced to 51 months in prison. Frank Durkan represented the defendants, along with attorney Michael Dowd.
    - Additional Government Discovery, Nov 20, 1990; 582938 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Amnesty International Reports, Jun 1991; 582939 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms (ATF) Investigations, circa 1989-1991; 582940 (Box 35, Folder 10, Folder 11)
    - Baldy, Tom F. Battle for Ulster, 1987; 582941 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Boyle, Francis A.: Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1990; 582972 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Boyle, Francis A. "The Decolonization of Northern Ireland", 1991; 582942 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Character Letters, 1990-1991; 582943 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1987-1991; 582944 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1994; 582945 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda [RESTRICTED], 1990; 582973 (Box 37, Folder 18, Folder 19)
    - Customs Service Investigation Reports, 1989; 582946 (Box 35, Folder 17, Folder 19, Folder 18)
    - Exhibits, 1990; 582947 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Investigative Reports, 1985-1987; 582948 (Box 35, Folder 21, Folder 23, Folder 22, Folder 24)
    - Memorandum in Opposition, 1990; 582949 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Motions: Defense, 1990; 582950 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Motions: Government, 1990; 582951 (Box 35, Folder 27, Folder 29, Folder 28, Folder 30)
    - Norwegian Helsinki Committee Report, 1990; 582953 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Notice of Objections, Feb 20, 1991; 582952 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Proceedings, 1990; 582954 (Box 36, Folder 1, Folder 2, Box 35, Folder 33, Folder 3)
    - Proceedings, Jan 19, 1990; 582955 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Proceedings, Jun 7, 1991; 582956 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Related Cases, 1982; 582957 (Box 36, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8)
    - Sentencing, 1991; 582958 (Box 36, Folder 9, Folder 10, Folder 11)
    - Wiretap Summary, 1990; 582959 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Wiretap Transcripts, 1989-1990; 582960 (Box 36, Folder 18, Folder 17, Folder 16, Folder 15, Folder 22, Folder 21, Folder 20, Folder 19, Folder 13, Folder 14)
- Series V. Durkan: Personal Files and Research, Written Work & Materials of Interest, 1920, 1957-2006; 327617
  This series contains material on topics of interest to Durkan, including the Great Famine in Ireland, shipwrecks of Irish coming to the Americas, his membership and activities in the Irish History Roundtable and a collection of his books, legal, history and sports-related. Also included is correspondence to and from Durkan on a a wide range of topics from letters to the editors of various publications and opinion pieces to letters of recommendation and personal matters. Additionally, a small collection of books which apparently belonged to Paul O'Dwyer, his uncle and head of the firm in which Durkan practiced law, are included in this series, many signed and/or annotated by the author.
  - Subseries A. Correspondence, Subject Files and Writings, 327619
    This series contains correspondence to and from Durkan, articles, speeches and letters to the editors, materials on topics of interest to Durkan and a few photographs. Materials in Box 29 were in very bad condition and most of the originals have been photocopied.
    - 1798 Rising, 1998-2000; 327621 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - 1798 Rising: Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1997-1998; 327622 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - 1798 Rising: Photographs, 1998; 327623 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - American Committee for Ulster Justice (ACUJ), 1974-1978; 327624 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - American Irish Unity Committee: Symposium (includes photographs), Jul 22, 1981; 327625 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Article: "The Hunger Strikers" / Hunger Strikers 25th Anniversary by Frank Durkan, 2006; 327733 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Articles and Speeches by Durkan, undated; 327732 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Articles, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings: general, 327626 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Ashe, Thomas: Banner unveiling (1918 Hunger Striker), Apr 2005; 327627 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Battle of Aughrim, 1691 (pamphlet), undated; 327628 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Brehon Law Society, 1981-1988; 327629 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Collins, Michael: Photograph, Armagh City, Sep 5, 1921; 334360 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Committee on the Administration of Justice, 1999-2003; 327987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Materials from Charlie McGrath, 1995; 582961 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1955; 334361 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1956; 334362 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional (Segregated), 1956; 334363 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1963-1970; 334364 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1967; 334365 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1975; 334366 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Personal and Professional, 1976; 334367 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - County Mayo, 1992-2003; 327631 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - County Mayo Association: Yearbook, 1988; 327632 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - County Mayo Football Championship Programs, 1992-2000; 327633 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - County Mayo: Lavan, Sean Thomas (1898-1973), 1996; 327634 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - County Mayo: Newspapers, 1995-1999; 327635 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Cuimhneachan 1916 - Commemoration of the 1916 Rising. Friends of Irish Freedom and Sean Ogliagh Na Heireann Heritage Association., Apr 15, 1990; 327991 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Curran, Moira: Deportation, includes family papers, John Curran. (Hugh O'Rourke of O'Dwyer Bernstien handled this case), 1897-1981; 334368 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Duffy, Jimmy: assorted articles and documents; includes DeValera statement (photocopy) and James Shea memoirs, 1923-2002; 327636 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Duffy, Jimmy: transcription, paper re: George Harrison; poems, 2004, undated; 327637 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - East Mayo Brigade IRA: Commemorative Memorial, Apr 7, 1958; 328203 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Emmett, Robert, 2001-2004; 327638 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Emmett, Robert, 2002; 327639 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Famine Pot, 2001; 327640 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Gaelic Gotham: Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1996; 327641 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Gaelic Gotham: Media Package, 1995-1996; 327642 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Gaelic Gotham Report: "Assessing a Controversial Exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York, 1997; 327643 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Grosse Ile, Canada I (Famine Quarantine Island), 1994-2001; 327644 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Grosse Ile, Canada II (Famine Quarantine Island), 1994-2001; 327645 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Grosse Ile, 1984-1996; 327646 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Harrison, George, 2002; 328220 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Honors and Memberships, 1992, undated; 327647 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Horizon Halfway House, 1995; 582962 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Irish Famine, 1845-1850, 1995-1997; 327649 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Irish Famine Cathedral Cemetery, Scranton, PA, 1964, undated; 327650 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Irish Famine: Choctaw and Irish Together (CAIT)- International Humanitarian Organization, 1996; 327689 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Irish Famine: County Mayo Killala Memorial, 1997; 327690 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Irish Famine: Genocide Curriculum, 1997-1999; 327691 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Jenkinson, Noel: Durkan Speech at Commemoration, Nov 14, 1976; 334369 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Keane, James, 1920, 1987 (Box Shared Tamiment 030, Folder 18)
    - Kelly, Nicky, 1989-1990; 327692 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Laverty, Chuck: Research Query (Mayo football player), 1997; 327693 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Martin Sheridan Memorial Committee (Olympian; NYPD), 1908-1996; 327694 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Martin Sheridan Memorial Committee (Olympian; NYPD): Photographs (grave), circa 1996; 327695 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Mayo Society of New York, 1991-2004; 327696 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - McDonnell, John J.: Correspondence re: Irish Memorabilia collection; includes photocopy of "The Story of the 1916 Proclamation" by John O'Connor., 1997; 327997 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Meagher, Thomas Francis (1823-1867): Article from Eire Ierland, Bulletin of the Department of External Affairs., 1967; 334370 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Molly Maguires, 1976-1984; 327697 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - National Graves Association (Ireland), 1981, undated; 327698 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - New York Irish History Roundtable: Article and Newspaper Clippings I, 1983-1996; 327699 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - New York Irish History Roundtable: Articles and Newspaper Clippings II, 1983-1996; 327700 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - New York Irish History Roundtable: Correspondence, 1991-1995; 327701 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - New York Irish History Roundtable: Newsletter, Calendar, 1988-2001; 327702 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters: The Irish Volunteer; Massachusetts Irish Volunteers, Ohio Irish Times, 1992-2002; 327703 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings: various, 1995-1999; 327704 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - O'Dwyer, Paul: Times Herald-Record story; photograph, 1995; 327705 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Irish Institute, John Gaughan Commemoration; Paul O'Dwyer and Hon Gwyner Evans, Wales, 1976; 334371 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Photoprint: "Support Irish Republicans in Jail for Ireland", undated; 327999 (Box 23, Box 10)
    - Research, 1914-1993; 327707 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Research Papers (by Rona Fields?): Irish Immigrants; Irish Republicanism from the 1980s?, undated; 334372 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Rural Resettlement Ireland!, 1993-1994; 582963 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Saint Patrick's Day Parade: Michael Flannery Controversy, 1983; 327708 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Saint Patrick's Day Parade: Michael Flannery Controversy: Newspaper Clippings, 1983; 327709 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Sharpton, Al: Irish Voice response by Durkan to "The O'Bradaigh Visa and Al Sharpton", Jun 1995; 327710 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Sinn Fein, 1995-1998; 327711 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - The Wreck of the St. John, Cohasset, MA (famine ship) 1849, 1984; 327731 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Subseries B: Books, Pamphlets and Publications, 327620
    - Aghaidh Achadh Mor: The Face of Aghamore (water damaged; some pages stuck together), undate; 327998 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - American Connection: U.S. Guns, Money and Influence in Northern Ireland. Jack Holland. Penguin Books, New York. inscription: "to the Florida Four with best wishes from Geroge Harrison", 1987; 327794 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - American Connection: U.S. Guns, Money and Influence in Northern Ireland. Jack Holland. Penguin. Dublin., 1989; 327795 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - "An Act for the Attainder of the Rebels in Ireland" Parliament, Westminster, London., 1657; 327706 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Bold Robert Emmett, 1778-1803. Sean o'Bradaigh. Irish Freedom Press. Inscription: "To Monica and Frank Salud George Harrison", 2003; 327796 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Breaking the Deadlock: A Way Out of the Northern Impasse. Robert Heatley. Fulcrum Press. Dublin., 1991; 327962 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Britain's War Machine in Ireland. Maurice Burke. Oisin Publications. New York., 1987; 327963 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - The Committee: Political Assassination in Northern Ireland. Sean McPhilemy. Roberts Rinehart Publishers, Niwot, CO. (includes many notes and annotations), circa 1998; 328008 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Cory Collusion Inquiry Report. Chief Superintendent Breen and Superintendent Buchanan, Oct 2003; 327993 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Creating a New Ireland as Reflected in the Writings of William Hughes. Hughes Enterprises, Baltimore., 1995; 328022 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Dilseacht: The Story of Comdt. General Tom Macguire and the Second (All-Ireland) Dail. Ruairi O'Bradaigh. Irish Freedom Press. (2 copies) One includes inscription: "To Monica and Frank from your friend George Harrison, New York, 5.20.97", 1997; 327797 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Eire Nua: A New Democracy. Republican Sinn Fein., 2000; 327798 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Human Rights in Northern Ireland: A Helsinki Watch Report. Human Rights Watch., 1991; 328023 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hunger Strike Commemoratives: Terence MacSwiney, 1920; 1980-1981 Hunger Strike, 1995, 2001; 327759 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Inishmurray: Gale, Stone and Fire - Portrait of a Fabled Island. Joe McGowan, Aeolus, 1998; 327792 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - An Introduction to Irish Research. Irish Ancestry: A Beginner's Guide. Bill Davis. Federation of Family Historical Societies, 1994; 327793 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - The IRA 1926-1936. Brian Hanley. Four Courts Press. Inscription: "To George, Thanks and Best Wishes from Brian Hanley Nov' 2003", 2002; 327800 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - The Irish Crisis. C. Desmond Greaves. Inernational Publishers. New York., 1972; 327801 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - The Irish in America. An Address by William T. Collins, Jusitce, Supreme Court, State of New York. At the Forum of National Democractic Club., Mar 9, 1935; 327789 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Journal of Prisoners on Prisons. Vol. 7, No. 2, 1996-1997; 328024 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - The McGarrity Papers: Revelations of the Irish revolutionary movement in Ireland and American 1900-1940. Sean Cronin. Anvil Books. Tralee. Co. Kerry, 1972; 328009 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Moore's Irish Melodies. ed. M.W. Balfe. Novello and Co., Ltd. London, undated; 334359 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "A New Beginning: Policing in Northern Irleand" The Report of the Independent Commission on Policing for Northern Ireland. (2 copies), Sep 1999; 327990 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - North Mayo Historical Journal, Vol II, No. 1. North Mayo Historical and Archaeological Society., 1987-1988; 327791 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "Northern Ireland: A Report to the Association of the Bar of the City of New York from a Mission of the Committee on International Human Rights.", Jun 1999; 327758 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - "Notes on Guerilla Warfare: A Handbook for Volunteers of the Irish Republican Army. IRA, 1956; 327734 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - O'Brien Pocket History of The Troubles. Brian Feeney. The O'Brien Press Ltd., Dublin., 2004; 327804 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "Omos Do Tony D'Arcy, Galway and Sean MacNeela, Mayo", 1990; 327790 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - The Patten Commission: A Submission by the People of West Belfast at Whiterock Nov., 1998. Upper Springfield Development Trust., 1999; 327992 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - The Rock from which you were Hewn: A history of the Catholic Church in Lewis County West Virginia St. Patrick's Parish, Weston by Donal O'Donovan. McClain Pringint Company, Parsons, WV., 1989; 327807 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Sheltering the Fugitive? The Extradition of Irish Political Offenders. Michael Farrell. Mercier Press, Cork and Dublin., 1985; 327803 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Sports: Programs: Connacht Senior Football Championship Leitrim vs. New York, 2003; National Football League 2000/2001 Finals (Ireland); Victory Dinner Dance Mayo Gaelic Football Club of New York, 2005; Books: The Championship Hurling and Football 1999: The Complete Record. Brian Carthy. 1999; Famous All-Irelands Book 2. Canavaun Books. 1984. (2 folders), 1984-2005; 328934 (Box 24, Folder 20-21)
    - "Why the British Kill American Presidents" The New Federalist. Leesburg, VA., Dec 1994; 327735 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - The Wreck of the British Queen. Robert F. Mooney. Mill Hill Press, 1988; 327788 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Years of Glory: Story of Kerry's All-Ireland Successes. John Barry and Eamon Horan. Self-published., 1977; 327805 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Subseries C: Paul O'Dwyer Book Collection, 327951
    - Arming the Protestants: The Formation of the Ulster Special Constabulary and the Royal Ulster Constabulary 1920-1927. Michael Farrell. Brandon Book Publishers, Ltd., Co, Kerry, Ireland. Inscription: To Paul O'Dwyer with best wishes Michael Farrell", 1983; 327952 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - The Battle of Long Island ("The Battle of Brooklyn"). Charles G. Teveson and Irene H. Wilson. Brooklyn Bicentennial Commission. Incription: To Paul O'Dywer with all best wished Joe Palin, Chariman", 1975; 327953 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Cage Eleven. Gerry Adams with an Introduction by Paul O'Dwyer (1993). Sheridan Square Press, New York., 1990; 327954 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - A Pathway to Peace. Gerry Adams, MP. Mercier Press. Cork and Dublin. (includes letter on Sinn Fein Letterhead from Adams), 1988; 327955 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Sandhogs: A History of the Tunnel Workers of New York. Paul E. Delaney. The Longfield Press. New York. Inscription: "To Paul O'Dwyer A fine Sandhog. One of the best friends the Sandhogs ever had. Sincerely Yours Richie Fitzsimmons" (includes Fitzsimmons' business card), 1983; 327956 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Twenty Years On. Edited by Michael Farrell. Brandon Book Publishers Ltd., Co. Kerry, Ireland. Inscription: "To Paul O'Dwyer with every best wish a colleague in the struggle for justice Michael Farrell", 1988; 327957 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Series VI. Oversize Items, 328432
  This series contains mostly newspapers with articles relating to legal cases represented in the collection or personal interest pieces of Durkan.
  - Irish Times, Dublin, Sep 1, 1994 - Sep 2, 1994; 328440 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Irish Times articles: "Northern Ireland Settlement"; "Belfast Agreement Referendums", Apr 11, 1998, May 25, 1998; 328439 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - The Mayo News: "Mayo in the 20th Century", Dec 1999; 328436 (Box 26, Folder 3)